THEMBA MTSHELWANE.

Johannesburg, Gauteng • 084 480 4140

Thembamm3@gmail.com • <u>GitHub</u> • <u>Portfolio Website</u>

SUMMARY.

Driven and skilled Software Developer with a BSc (Hons) in Information Engineering. I am advancing my expertise as a Software Developer Intern at Tshimologong, specializing in creating responsive, user-focused websites. I am committed to solving complex problems and enhancing user experiences through innovative, efficient code.

EDUCATION.

Bachelor of Science in (Electrical) Information Engineering, 2024 University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg.

WORK EXPERIENCE.

Software Developer Intern.

Tshimologong - Digital Innovation Precinct
Johannesburg | July 2024 - Present
Katlego Molala| katlego@tshimologong.joburg

- Currently working as a frontend/full-stack web developer, focusing on creating responsive and dynamic websites using React, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, NodeJS and Express.
- I am currently leading my team in developing a creative writing website. Setting up meetings, delegating and tracking tasks through Trello.

Full-Stack Developer.

Freelance

Online | Feb 2023 - Feb 2024

Philippe Ferrer | philippe.ferrer@wists.ac.za | 011 717 6865

- Independently developed two demos of Learning Management System (LMS) websites using React, NextJS, Chakra UI, and Firebase.
- The quizzes are in a Binary Tree format allowing to isolate a student's problem area.

Teaching Assistant.

University of the Witwatersrand
Johannesburg | Sep 2023 - Nov 2023
Stephen Levitt | stephen.levitt@wits.ac.za | 011 717 7209

- Assisted in marking and reviewing code which included student labs and projects written in C++ using SFML and Doctest.
- Developed effective communication skills by conveying complex technical concepts to students. Concepts such as Object Oriented Programming, Unit Tests, MVC architecture.

SKILLS.

Technical Skills.

- Front-end Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Context API and Zustand.
- Back-end Development: Express, NodeJS and REST-full APIs.
- Version Control: GitHub.
- Database: Firebase, MongoDB and SQL.
- Figma and Trello.
- AI prompting.

Soft Skills.

- Great communication skills.
- Problem-solving.
- Flexibility and Adaptability.
- Creativity and Critical Thinking.
- Time Management and Planning
- Attention to Detail.